HANSEN MASON WEB DEVELOPER

Employment

General Assembly

Boston, MA Jan. 2019 to Apr. 2019

Web Development Immersive

- -Experience with HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuery, Ruby, Rails involving front-end, back-end, and full-stack development
- -Learned problem solving strategies, utilizing resources, applying learned concepts, how and where to find solutions to problems
- -Over 500+ hours of classroom learning and application including studies, diagnostics, challenges, and projects
- -Created four major projects, three independent projects and one team project, that are deployed through github
- -Team-oriented interactive learning that demonstrates collaborative problem solving and how to work in groups as well as independently

Cook. Restaurants

Newton, MA Mar. 2018 to Dec. 2018

Server

אמו. בטוס נט שפנ. ב -Trained new hires in POS system, customer services, and efficient multitasking

- -Treated all customer requests with equal importance to help ensure customer satisfaction
- -Answered all questions and offered suggestions based on customer needs

Wayfair

Boston, MA Apr. 2016 to Nov. 2016

Business Account Development

- -Started and managed a book of business through regular outbound calls and e-mails
- -Met monthly revenue and management goals while maximizing margins and minimizing costs
- -Excelled in customer service as the main point of contact for clients purchasing needs and service issues

Projects

TicTacToe

- -User features of sign up, sign in, change password, and sign out
- -Interactive tic tac toe board that updates as areas are clicked, establishing winner or draw
- -Successfully stores each game played in a database for future access through api interaction
- -Keeps track of win scores of current session between users
- -Gives total win count for signed-in user from all sessions ever played

Book Clubs!

- -User features same as TicTacToe
- -Set up front end and back end as a full stack project
- -Created own relational database using SQL with users and book clubs as resources
- -Set up book clubs to users where book clubs belongs to users
- -Generated search bar for book clubs to find, delete, and update by name

Letterbox - Group Project

- -Worked as a team to build fullstack with NOSQL database (mongo with expressjs)
- -All user functions with users, blogs, and comments as resources
- -Added features such as liking blogs, blog sorting by amount of likes/time blog was posted
- -Other features included handle for users, with search blogs by title, content, and/or handle
- -Practiced group skills involving communication, pair programming, planning, and scrum

Pico Fermi - Final Project

- -Built a full stack guessing number game
- -Used react in the front end and ruby on rails in the back end
- -Two different game types, each with their own back end route and schema
- -Used react for routing and rendering, on a SPA

Skills

Html

CSS

JavaScript

jQuery

Ruby

Bootstrap

Handlebars

React

Express

Ruby on Rails

Education

Trinity College Sept. 2009 to May 2013
Bachelor of Science Neuroscience 2013
3.5 GPA

Activities

Golfing

Surfing

Reading

Soccer

Summary

I am a junior software developer. Coming from a neuroscience background, with a number of different jobs, I have experienced myriad fields and had not found anything that I was ready to dedicate myself toward. After hearing about software engineering through friends and family, I decided to take online courses. Immediately I knew this was something I was interested in, and definitely has my attention. I really enjoy the problem solving aspect of this field, while aligning with many core values I hope for in a job. It is already very rewarding and I look forward to learning as much as I can within the field, and beyond. I hope to be involved in fullstack development.

Contact

- hansenmason3@gmail.com
- **2078416797**
- **♀** Boston, MA
- **f** hansenmmason
- hansenmason